Catalog of the Literary Manuscripts in The Oscar Lion Collection of Walt Whitman, The New York Public Library
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- Like Earth O River Sailing Down the Mississippi, nyp.00106; xxx.00671; xxx.00522; poetry 1 leaf handwritten
  Eight lines, in neat handwriting, comparing a river—probably the Mississippi, which is referenced in the seven lines written on the verso—to "Earth" and "Time." The relation of these lines to Whitman's published work is unclear.
- Remember how many pass Remember how many pass their whole lives, nyp.00097; xxx.00680; poetry 1 leaf handwritten
  Two lines, with revisions, toward a composition that was never published. This scrap used to be part of the same manuscript as the one titled "Have you known that" in this collection.
- undulating undulating swiftly merging from womb to birth, nyp.00116; xxx.00686; poetry 1 leaf handwritten
  A collection of notes on what seem to be three different topics: acts of "merging" suggestive of sexual union; stars moving in their orbits; shame felt by an African American for his or her "wooly head."